(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
作詞：R-指定　作曲：DJ松永
To Those of Us Who Used to Be Geniuses
Lyrics: R-Shitei, Composer: DJ Matsunaga
泣いてたとか　怖いとか　気づかなければ
If I hadn't realized I was crying or scared,
俺だって　ボルトと友達になれた
Even I could have been friends with Bolt.
頭が悪いとか　思わなけりゃ
If I hadn't thought I was stupid,
きっとファインマン　ゼネフらと解けた
I surely could have solved things with Feynman or Zenef.
スベリ倒した　マサヤには　笑わなけりゃ
If I hadn't laughed at Masaya who slipped,
ずっと小松の茶に酔ってた
I'd have been drunk on Komatsu's tea forever.
力が弱いとか　独裁とか　知らなきゃ
If I didn't know about weakness or dictatorship,
俺が　地球を守ってた
I would have been the one protecting the Earth.
背ぇ破り過ぎた　あの落書きや
Those drawings I tore out because they were too much,
似合わないと言われた　髪型
And the hairstyle I was told didn't suit me.
うろ覚えの下手くそな　歌が
My half-remembered, clumsy singing
世界を変えたかも
Might have changed the world.
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
To us who were once geniuses,
神童だった貴方へ
To you who were once a prodigy.
似たような形に整えられて
Molded into similar shapes,
見る影も無い
Not a trace of our former selves remains.
いまだかつてないほど　入り組んだ way way way
A path more convoluted than ever before, way way way
悩めるだけ悩み
Worry as much as you need to,
時が来たら　かませ
And when the time comes, go for it!
風まかせ　どっちみち茨の way way way
Let the wind take you; either way it's a thorny way way way
俺らは大器晩成
We are late bloomers;
時が来たら　かませ
When the time comes, go for it!
I wanna be a 勝者　I wanna be a 強者
I wanna be a winner, I wanna be a powerhouse
まだ見ぬ高みへ　駆け込み乗車
Hopping on the train to heights yet unseen
花火のような　運命だろうが
Even if it's a fate like fireworks,
我が身果てるまで　やりきれそいや　yeah
I'll keep going until my body gives out, yeah!
生まれてこの方　一体幾つ
Since I was born, just how many
不便を見過ごしてきたんだろうか
Inconveniences have I overlooked until now?
墓場に入るまで　あと一体幾つ
Until I enter the grave, just how many
可能性の芽を摘んでしまうのだろうか
Seeds of possibility will I end up crushing?
一体幾つ　獣を解き放てるだろうか
How many beasts can I unleash?
今はまだ　見にくいアヒルの子
Right now, I'm still an ugly duckling.
ほらどうぞ　鞭とご鞭撻を
Go ahead, give me your whip and guidance.
ほらまた　世間の洗礼を浴びるとこ
Here I am again, about to be baptized by the public.
俺はキャンバス　かなり汚れちまったけれど
I'm a canvas, quite stained now but
ワンチャンス
One chance,
その余白はあるさ　ちゃっかり
There's still some blank space, quite cleverly.
目当たり　胴当たり　この隔たりを　永久に
Colliding head-on, torso-on, this gap, eternally.
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
To us who were once geniuses,
神童だった貴方へ
To you who were once a prodigy.
何だってなれた　another way
We could have been anything, another way,
まだ諦めちゃいない
I haven't given up yet.
いまだかつてないほど　入り組んだ way way way
A path more convoluted than ever before, way way way
悩めるだけ悩み
Worry as much as you need to,
時が来たら　かませ
And when the time comes, go for it!
風まかせ　どっちみち茨の way way way
Let the wind take you; either way it's a thorny way way way
俺らは大器晩成
We are late bloomers;
時が来たら　かませ
When the time comes, go for it!
I wanna be a 勝者　I wanna be a 強者
I wanna be a winner, I wanna be a powerhouse
まだ見ぬ高みへ　駆け込み乗車
Hopping on the train to heights yet unseen
花火のような　運命だろうが
Even if it's a fate like fireworks,
我が身果てるまで　やりきれそいや　yeah
I'll keep going until my body gives out, yeah!
お前は今だに　広がり続ける銀河
You are still an ever-expanding galaxy.
孫の代までずっと　フレッシュマン
A freshman forever, even to your grandchildren's generation.
粗探しが得意な　お国柄
In a country where finding faults is the national trait,
しかとでかまそうぜ　金輪際
Let's just ignore it and go for it from now on.
俺も今だに　広がり続ける銀河
I am also still an ever-expanding galaxy.
今は亡き奴までずっと　フレッシュマン
Even those who are gone are freshmen forever.
くたばり損ねて　冥土からカムバック
Failing to die and coming back from the underworld,
草葉の陰から　ゴーン・フィンガー
A gone finger from behind the scenes.
無傷のままじゃいられない
You can't stay unscathed.
変わり続けていく　多面体
A polyhedron that keeps changing.
その物差しじゃ　測れない
You can't measure it with that ruler.
測らせる気も無い
And I have no intention of letting you.
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
To us who were once geniuses,
神童だった貴方へ
To you who were once a prodigy.
まだ見ぬ明日へ　羽ばたけ　いくぜ
Fly towards a tomorrow yet unseen, here we go:
one two three four five
いまだかつてないほど　入り組んだ way way way
A path more convoluted than ever before, way way way
悩めるだけ悩み
Worry as much as you need to,
時が来たら　かませ
And when the time comes, go for it!
風まかせ　どっちみち茨の way way way
Let the wind take you; either way it's a thorny way way way
俺らは大器晩成
We are late bloomers;
時が来たら　かませ
When the time comes, go for it!
はい、ということで、皆さん、こんまっする！
Yes, so, hello everyone, Kon-muscle!
ホロライブ3期生の鉄の揺らぐ、逞しい！
Hololive 3rd Gen's iron-wavering, powerful!
白銀ノエルです！マッスル、マッスル、マッスル！
It's Shirogane Noel! Muscle, muscle, muscle!
ということで、えーと、団長今回、リリカルライブ開催です！イェイ！
And so, um, Danchou's Lyrical Live is being held this time! Yay!
えーっと、最初の曲はですね、「かつて天才だった俺たちへ」ということで、
Um, the first song was "To Us Who Were Once Geniuses",
団長の、大好きな、あの、Creepy Nutsさんの曲です。
it's a song by Creepy Nuts, who Danchou loves very much.
ま、この曲、あの、見ての通り、あの、振り付けとか、あの、即興で考えて、
Well, this song, as you can see, I thought of the choreography on the spot,
もうダンスとかではないんですけど、ちょっとね…
so it's not really a dance or anything, but...
あれ、団長、ダンスとか頑張ったって言ってたのに、
Hey, Danchou said she'd work hard on dancing,
あれ、ダンスしてないじゃんって思ったそこの君。
but she's not dancing at all. You there, thinking that.
えーっと、ダンスは、次の曲から、行きます！
Um, the dancing starts from the next song!
ちょっとね、リリックに乗って、ちょっと、イマジナリーなね、
Just riding the lyrics, I feel like an imaginary Danchou
団長も、ちょっと、映った気が、した気がするんですけど…
also appeared for a bit, I think...
ま、ね、ちょっと、団長、ちょっと、ダンスのね、ちょっと、ダンスしない代わりに、
Well, um, Danchou, instead of dancing,
ちょっと、うーん、イマジナリーということでね。はい、ちょっと、分身を出しました。
well, it's imaginary. Yes, I brought out some clones.
次は、歌って、踊って、アイドルとか、するのかな？
Next, will I sing, dance, and be an idol?
どうなんでしょうか。
I wonder.
さて、じゃあ、ちょっと、場所を移動して、リリカルライブスタートしましょう。
Well then, let's move locations and start the Lyrical Live.
もしよければ、ハッシュタグで、たくさん、スクショとか、ツイートしてください。
If you'd like, please take lots of screenshots and tweet them with the hashtag.
ではでは、リリカルライブ、スタート！
Now then, Lyrical Live, start!
うらら、路地裏のアンバランス、慣れない景色と好かない匂いに...
Urara, the imbalance of the back alley, to the unfamiliar scenery and unpleasant smell...
私は追われて染まってゆくのでしょう
I will surely be chased and dyed.
私は怖がりで、知らないことには手を付けず
I'm a coward, I don't touch things I don't know.
誰かがやってきて、毒見をするまで待っていた
I waited until someone came along and tasted the poison.
することは単純で、マニュアル通りのな生活を
What I do is simple, a life according to the manual.
来る日も淡々と、過ごしていた
I spent my days indifferently.
そいやさそいやさ、昨日の私もこうだった
Soiyasa, soiyasa, yesterday I was like this too.
そいやさそいやさ
Soiyasa, soiyasa
弱い音を吐いている、薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow human who spits out weak sounds.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます、絡まれたくはないからさ
I'll stop stepping forward, because I don't want to get involved.
描いた理想像に、現実味がないから
Because my envisioned ideal is unrealistic.
近づかないよう生きときます、明日も同じよう過ごしときます
I'll live my life without getting close, I'll spend tomorrow the same way.
路地裏の真ん中で、いつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて
In the middle of the back alley, I look at the usual sunset with narrowed eyes.
胸の内で呟いた、いつまで続くだろう
I murmured in my heart, I wonder how long it will last.
そいやさそいやさ、昨日の夕飯これだった
Soiyasa, soiyasa, yesterday's dinner was this.
そいやさそいやさ
Soiyasa, soiyasa
臆病で切りが悪い、意気地なし人間です
I'm a spineless, cowardly human who doesn't know when to quit.
一歩後ろに下がって逃げときます、目立ちたくなんかないからさ
I'll step back and run away, because I don't want to stand out.
描いた理想像に、現実味がないから
Because my envisioned ideal is unrealistic.
近づかないよう生きときます、明日も同じよう過ごしときます
I'll live my life without getting close, I'll spend tomorrow the same way.
弱い音を吐いている、薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow human who spits out weak sounds.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます、絡まれたくはないからさ
I'll stop stepping forward, because I don't want to get involved.
ため息ばっかで、吸う息足りないの
I'm only sighing, I don't have enough breath to inhale.
そう上手くはいかないけどさ、試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
It won't go that well, but let's try to live properly.
No Logic / 作詞・作曲 ジミーサムP
No Logic / Lyrics and Music by JimmyThumbP
だいたいそれでいいんじゃないの
Probably that's fine, isn't it?
適当だっていいんじゃないの
Being casual is fine too, isn't it?
少し不安を残したほうが
Leaving a bit of uncertainty
楽しく生きられるんじゃないの
Might make life more enjoyable, won't it?
疲れたら寝ればいいんじゃないの
If you're tired, just sleep, isn't that fine?
たまには楽していいんじゃないの
It's okay to take it easy sometimes, isn't it?
やりたいことやるために
To do what we want to do
僕らは生きているんでしょう
That's why we're living, right?
だいたいそれでいいんじゃないの
Probably that's fine, isn't it?
失敗してもいいんじゃないの
It's okay to fail, isn't it?
どんなに悩んだってほら
No matter how much you worry, see
結局タイミングなんじゃないの
In the end, it's all about timing, isn't it?
ひとつひとつ抱え込んで
Carrying everything one by one
いったい何をどうしたいの
What on earth do you want to do?
やりたいことやるために
To do what you want to do
君は生まれてきたんでしょう
That's why you were born, right?
完璧な生き方なんてできないから
Because we can't live perfectly
完璧な生き方なんてしたくないから
Because we don't want to live perfectly
不器用な 僕は不器用な
Clumsy... I'm clumsy
ままでいい
Just as I am is fine
神様 この歌が聞こえるかい
God, can you hear this song?
あなたが望んでいなくても
Even if you don't wish for it
僕は笑っていたいんです
I want to be laughing
泣きたい時は泣きたいんです
I want to cry when I want to cry
いつだって自然体でいたいね
I want to be myself, always
誰もが二度と戻れぬ今を
The "now" that no one can ever return to
きっといつか後悔するから
We'll surely regret it someday
今はまだこんな気持ちで
So for now, with these feelings
そよ風に歩いていたっていいよね
It's okay to just walk in the breeze, right?
だいたいそれでいいんじゃないの
Probably that's fine, isn't it?
無理はしなくていいんじゃないの
You don't have to push yourself, right?
作り笑いしたってほら
Even if you fake a smile, see
ちっとも楽しくないでしょ
It's not fun at all, is it?
ひとつひとつ抱え込んで
Carrying everything one by one
いったい何をどうしたいの
What on earth do you want to do?
誰もが100点満点の
No one can give
答えなんて出せないでしょう
A perfect 100-point answer, right?
完璧な生き方なんてできないから
Because we can't live perfectly
完璧な生き方なんてしたくないから
Because we don't want to live perfectly
不完全な 僕は不完全な
Incomplete... I'm incomplete
ままでいい
Just as I am is fine
神様 この歌が聞こえるかい
God, can you hear this song?
あなたが望んでいなくても
Even if you don't wish for it
僕は笑っていたいんです
I want to be laughing
そして今叫びたいんです
And now I want to scream
いつだって最後は No Logic
In the end, it's always "No Logic"
僕らのこの一度きりの夢
This one-time dream of ours
どうせいつか終わりが来るなら
If an end will come anyway
生きること辞めたい時だけ
Only when you want to stop living
立ち止まって考えるくらいで
Is it okay to just stop and think
いいよね
Right?
やりたいことだけ選んで
Choosing only what I want to do
いらないもの切り捨てて
Casting aside what I don't need
誰もがみんなそんな風に
No one can possibly
歩けるわけないよね
Walk that way, right?
はーい、はい。えーと、聴いてくださりありがとうございます。
Alright, yes. Um, thank you for listening.
「No Logic」でした。
That was "No Logic."
その1個前はね、「ヨワネハキ」聴いていただきました。
Before that, you heard "Yowanehaki."
いや、結構団長「ヨワネハキ」は配信で結構歌ってるから
Well, I sing "Yowanehaki" quite often in my streams,
ちょっとこの曲、ライブバージョンはこんな感じかって思ってくれた団員さんいると思うけど
so I think some of you knights might have thought, "Oh, so this is what the live version is like."
「No Logic」はね、たぶん初めて歌ったと思うんですけど
But for "No Logic," I think it's the first time I've sung it,
ちょっとすごいね、めちゃめちゃ団長好きな曲で
it's a song I really, really love,
なんか「人生」っていう感じがして
it feels like "life" to me.
いや正直ね、ライブのもっと後ろに持ってきたほうがよかったかなって
Honestly, maybe I should have put it later in the live...
ちょっと冒頭でちょっと人生語っちゃったなーと思いつつ
Thinking I might have talked about life too much at the beginning,
ま、これからね、ちょっとあれです、この通常衣装とはおさらばし
well, from here on, I'll be saying goodbye to this regular outfit.
ちょっとね、結構歌ったり踊ったりな
And then, I'll be singing and dancing...
ちょっとアイドルっぽくなってこうかなと思ってますので
becoming a bit more idol-like,
引き続きハッシュタグいっぱい...
so please continue using the hashtag...
ハッシュタグつけてツイートしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you could tweet with the hashtag!
では、参ります！
Well then, here we go!
眠るサカナ
作詞・作曲：Fullkawa Head.Q.music
Nemuru Sakana (Sinking Fish)
Lyrics/Composition: Fullkawa Head.Q.music
夜が来た 眠れずに 今日も
Night has come, unable to sleep, today too
雨降り降り、振られて。
The rain falls and falls, I'm stood up.
待ちぼうけ 一人のベッドに
Waiting in vain, in a bed all alone
沈むサカナ
A sinking fish
今夜窓から抜け出したのは
The one who slipped out the window tonight
白い渡り鳥
Was a white migratory bird
夜風に揺れる羽根にくるまって
Wrapped in feathers swaying in the night breeze
目を閉じた
I closed my eyes
眠れない夜はこうやって
On nights I can't sleep, like this,
君を思い出してみる
I try to remember you
会えない日々もそうやって
Even on days we can't meet, like that,
隠してきた
I've been hiding it
傘を開いて窓を叩くよ
Opening an umbrella, I'll knock on the window
裸足のまま連れ出すんだ。
I'll lead you out while still barefoot.
部屋の明かりを消したら
Once the lights in the room are turned off
手を伸ばして、さあ！
Reach out your hand, come on!
踊り出すミュージック！
The music starts to dance!
夜が来た 一人きり 今日も
Night has come, all alone, today too
雨降り濡れたままで
While still wet from the rain
君の手を思い出しながら
While remembering your hand
眠るサカナ
A sleeping fish
眠れない夜はこうやって
On nights I can't sleep, like this,
君を思い浮かべてみる
I try to imagine you
会えない日々はそうやって
Even on days we can't meet, like that,
隠してきた
I've been hiding it
窓を叩く雨にまぎれたら
If I blend into the rain hitting the window
裸足のまま泳いでいくよ
I'll swim away while still barefoot
部屋の明かりを消したら
Once the lights in the room are turned off
手を伸ばして！
Reach out your hand!
眠れない夜はこうやって
On nights I can't sleep, like this,
君を思い出してみる
I try to remember you
会えない日々もそうやって
Even on days we can't meet, like that,
隠してきた
I've been hiding it
傘を開いて窓を叩くよ
Opening an umbrella, I'll knock on the window
裸足のまま連れ出すんだ。
I'll lead you out while still barefoot.
部屋の明かりを消したら
Once the lights in the room are turned off
手を伸ばして、さあ！
Reach out your hand, come on!
踊り出すミュージック！
The music starts to dance!
お願いジュンブライト
Onegai June Bright
ガラス窓の向こう側に
Beyond the glass window
十字架と海が見える
I can see a cross and the sea
君は仕事仲間たちに
Your coworkers are...
シャンパンをつがれている
...serving you champagne
君のパパに泣かれた時
When your father cried for us
胸の奥で誓ったよ
I made a vow in my heart
この愛を
This love...
...This love...
大切に守り抜くと
...I will protect it forever
思い出が輝いてここにあるかぎり
As long as these memories stay shining here
いつまでも変わらない あの頃のまま
They'll never change, just as they were then
お願いジュンブライト
Please, June Bright
あの時の君 透明な夏
You back then, in that transparent summer
空に投げたあのブーケで
With that bouquet thrown into the sky
幸せになれた人は
The person who found happiness
運命を
Destiny...
本当に信じてたから
...They truly believed in it
思い出が輝いてここにあるかぎり
As long as these memories stay shining here
いつまでも変わらない あの頃のまま
They'll never change, just as they were then
お願いジュンブライト
Please, June Bright
あの時の君 永遠の夏
You back then, in that eternal summer
Kissしてどんなときも
Kiss me, no matter when
笑顔で照らしていて
Keep lighting me up with your smile
好きだからこそする喧嘩
Squabbles because we love each other
それも大切
They are important too
思い出に灯をともし 語り明かそうよ
Let's light up our memories and talk all night
小さな子供達を膝に座らせ
With our little children sitting on our laps
お願いジュンブライト
Please, June Bright
あの時の君 透明な夏
You back then, in that transparent summer
あの時の君 永遠の愛
You back then, an eternal love
マシンガントーク
Machinegun Talk
ちょっとやそっとじゃ止まらない君のマシンガントーク
Your machine-gun talk won't stop for a little or a lot
時々迷惑に感じるくらい
To the point where I sometimes feel it's a nuisance
Please please don't disturb me
そんじょそこらの男たちには手にも負えないレベルの
At a level that ordinary men can't handle
You're my honey
僕にはわかってるんだよ
I know it,
それが君の愛のカタチ
that's your form of love
どんなに小さな出来事だって
Even the smallest event,
Please please tell me all about YOU
世界中の誰よりもずっと君のこと知っていたいから
Because I want to know about you more than anyone else in the world
シャワーのように降りかかる言葉の雨に打たれていたい
I want to be struck by the rain of words falling like a shower
GOOD TIME BAD TIME
いろいろあるけれど It's all right
There's a lot of things, but It's all right
キスして抱きしめてる時だけはホントに静かだね
Only when we kiss and hug, you're really quiet
I want you want
これ以上スキになるとヤバイ
It'll be bad if I like you any more than this
離れられない
I can't leave
ランチの合間も止まらない君のマシンガントーク
Your machine-gun talk won't stop even during lunch
冷めたコーヒーで乾きを潤し
Wetting your dry throat with cold coffee,
Please please tell me all about YOU
まるでコンタクトレンズのように君とずっと一緒にいるから
Because I'm with you all the time, just like a contact lens
疲れた心癒す言葉の海に溺れていたい
I want to drown in the sea of words that heals my tired heart
GOOD TIME BAD TIME
いろいろあるけれど It's OK
There's a lot of things, but It's OK
ケンカや誤解や仲直りホントに忙しいね
Fighting, misunderstanding, and making up, we're really busy
I want you want
大切なトキを二人で過ごそう
Let's spend precious time together
離れたくない
I don't want to leave
見えるものだけ信じちゃだめだよ
Don't believe only what you can see.
見えないものを見なきゃだめだよ
You must see what you can't see
聞こえることだけ信じるよりも
Rather than believing only what you can hear,
聞こえないことを聴いてかなきゃ
you must listen to what you can't hear
言葉の裏側に隠されてる真実がちゃんと見えてるかい
Can you see the truth hidden behind the words clearly?
そういうこと忘れずにいれば
If you keep that in mind...
GOOD TIME BAD TIME
いろいろあるけれど It's all right
There's a lot of things, but It's all right
キスして抱きしめてる時だけはホントに静かだね
Only when we kiss and hug, you're really quiet
I want you want
これ以上スキになるとヤバイ
It'll be bad if I like you any more than this
離れられない
I can't leave
GOOD TIME BAD TIME
いろいろあるけれど It's OK
There's a lot of things, but It's OK
ケンカや誤解や仲直りホントに忙しいね
Fighting, misunderstanding, and making up, we're really busy
I want you want
大切なトキを二人で過ごそう
Let's spend precious time together
離れたくない
I don't want to leave
あい〜！あい〜！
Ai~! Ai~!
わためー、今日は来ていただきありがとうございます！
Watame, thank you for coming today!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you very much too!
いやーね、もう、はい。
Well, yeah, okay.
団長、はい。
Danchou, yes.
何で呼ばれたんだろう、うん。
Why was I called, yeah.
えっとね、今日は、あの団長ね、ずっとずっとそのわためとね、歌って踊りたかった曲があって。
Um, today, Danchou had a song that I've wanted to sing and dance with Watame for a long, long time.
いや、わため、ま、さっきね、歌ったからちょっとわかると思うけど、ちょっとそれは一瞬忘れて、
Well, Watame, we just sang it so you might know, but let's forget that for a moment,
え、わためって好きなアーティストさん誰かな？
Um, Watame, who is your favorite artist?
えっと、ポルノグラフィティです！
Um, it's Porno Graffitti!
そうだね。ライブも見てたもんね。
That's right. You were watching the live too.
うん。
Yeah.
で、団長も実はポルノグラフィティ好きなんだよ。
And Danchou actually likes Porno Graffitti too.
なにっ！？
What!?
なんだってー！
What did you say!?
まあ！
My!
知ってると思うけど、それで一番好きな曲が、あのマシンガントークで。
I think you know this, but my favorite song is 'Machine Gun Talk'.
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
そう、だからね、ずっとずっと二人で歌ってみたいなと思っていました。
Yeah, so I've been wanting to sing it with you for a long time.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
いや本当に。
I really have.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
こちらこそ！こんなコアなね、ポルノの曲が歌えると思いませんでした。
Same here! I never thought we'd sing such a deep Porno track.
そう、すごいもう20年以上前の曲？
Yeah, it's a song from over 20 years ago, right?
ね。そんななんか、黒猫のアルバムの。
Right. It's from that 'Kuroneko' album.
そうそう、アルバムの曲で。
Yeah, yeah, an album track.
曲でね。やってくれてありがとうございます。
Yeah. Thanks for doing it with me.
こちらこそ。
The pleasure is mine.
今日はね、うん。今日あの、団長ちょっとわために、あとね、やりたいことがあって。
Today... Yeah, today I have something else I want to do with Watame.
え、何？
Eh, what?
あるんだけど。
There's something.
何々？
What is it, what is it?
ちょっと、でもなんか団長がちょっとね...
Well, but I'm a bit...
チュ、チューはあげないでしょ？
You're not gonna give me a k-kiss, are you?
違う、そんなことない。違うよ。
No, it's not that. You're wrong.
え、でもさ、この二人お揃いのTシャツ着れたし。
But look, we're wearing matching T-shirts.
いや、このTシャツね、でけぇよな。
Man, these T-shirts are huge, aren't they?
近くにね、離れたくない、近くに行っちゃおう。
I want to be close, I don't want to leave. I'm coming closer!
で、でかいね。
They are... big.
え、ちょっと、そういうのはなしで。そういうのなしで。
Wait a sec, none of that. Cut it out.
あ、なし？
Oh, not allowed?
なし！
Not allowed!
でもなんか、なんかわたおじ出てる？なんかじーっと見てるね。
But somehow... is 'Wata-oji' coming out? You're staring so hard.
なんか吸い込まれちゃ、目が勝手に吸い込まれちゃう。
I'm being sucked in... my eyes are just drawn to them.
ちょ、ちょっと何か、あ、これはいけませんね。
Wait, hold on... Ah, this won't do.
ギリわた、だめ。えい！
Giri-Wata, no! Take this!
いたーい！
Ouch!
YONA YONA DANCE
ダンスウィズ どのかた
Dance with someone
心通じ合っていく
Our hearts start to connect
さらけ出してちょうだい感情を
Please lay bare your emotions
手を鳴らして クラップ ユア ハンズ
Clap your hands and clap your hands
バックウィズ どのかた
Back with someone
ヨナヨナ踊っていこう
Let's dance night after night
今宵ノラりくらり自由奔放
Tonight, uninhibited and carefree
存在証明したい
I want to prove my existence
ならば踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Then it's a loss if you don't dance, it's a loss!
君と舞っていたい 舞っていたいだけです
I just want to dance with you, I just want to dance!
ならば踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Then it's a loss if you don't dance, it's a loss!
心躍れない毎日だって 私気に食わないわ
I can't stand the days when my heart won't dance
ミラーボール輝いて
The mirror ball is shining
心照らし合っていく
Illuminating our hearts
あばき出してちょうだい表情を
Please reveal your expressions
惹かれ合って 手を離さない
Attracted to each other, never letting go
洒落たビート溶かして
Melt into the stylish beat
舞い踊って最前線
Dance at the front line
今宵アらえらえ話して プレイバック 感謝じゃもったいない
Talking away tonight, playback... gratitude is a waste
故に踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Therefore, it's a loss if you don't dance, it's a loss!
君と舞っていたい 舞っていたいだけです
I just want to dance with you, I just want to dance!
故に踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Therefore, it's a loss if you don't dance, it's a loss!
たまにゃあってもいいわ
It's okay to have this once in a while
されど光れる声
And yet, a voice that can shine
誰も知らない声
A voice that nobody knows
どこまでも行けそうな
Feels like I can go anywhere
そんな日々を過ごして
Spending days like that
夜が明けては また繰り返す
The night ends and then repeats again
このままずっと
Just like this, forever
胸が騒ぐ方へ
Towards where my heart beats fast
故に踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Therefore, it's a loss if you don't dance, it's a loss!
君と舞っていたい 舞っていたいだけです
I just want to dance with you, I just want to dance!
故に踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Therefore, it's a loss if you don't dance, it's a loss!
心躍れない毎日だって 私気に食わないわ
I can't stand the days when my heart won't dance
腑抜けた心にI need you 噂のアルカロイド
To my spineless heart, I need you, the rumored alkaloid
あだ名はネットのしゃれこうべ かき鳴らせギトショウ
My nickname is 'The Internet's Skull', strum it, Gito-Show
付け焼き刃の侍が 乱れ打つ三段重
The samurai with a borrowed blade strikes in a chaotic three-tiered sequence
悲劇の歴史で踊ろうか ほらヘンテコヘンテコ前々！
Shall we dance through this tragic history? Look, it's weird, weird, forward, forward!
はあ！
Hah!
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度ナンセンス
My heart is an Ego Rock, a 45-degree angle of nonsense
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日にバイバイバイ
Crushing the know-how, breaking the rut, say bye-bye-bye to tomorrow
媚びへつらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That fawning appearance of yours is enough to make me sick
シニカルな視線の雨
A rain of cynical gazes
今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Pretending to cover both eyes again today
おちゃらけ頭にI need you 巷のアルカロイド
To my goofy head, I need you, the alkaloid of the streets
あの子も流行りのインスタンス 撒き散らせPRID
That girl too, a trendy instance, spread around the PRID
うなずき上がらぬ侍が 乱れ立つ愛闘座
The samurai who won't stop nodding, rising in a chaotic battle of love
無残な歴史で歌おうよ ほらちゃんちゃらちゃんちゃら前々！
Let's sing through this cruel history, look, it's a joke, a joke, forward, forward!
はあ！
Hah!
ロックな心で生きようか 真っ当なパトスのミュージック
Shall we live with a rock 'n' roll heart? The music of honest pathos
ハウツー砕いて丸書いて 明日もワッハッハ
Crushing the how-tos, drawing a circle, laughing 'Wah-ha-ha' tomorrow too
洒落臭さも癖になる
Even that affectation becomes a habit
はみ出し者だろう
Must be an outcast
リリカルな視線の雨
A rain of lyrical gazes
今日も両目を開くふり
Pretending to open both eyes again today
透明な感情は 染まるだけさ
Transparent emotions are just waiting to be dyed
だったら見て見ぬふりする奴らを 押し流せ
In that case, let's brush aside those who turn a blind eye
人生かけても負けそうです 勝ち負け取り繕うナンセンス
I feel like I'd lose even if I bet my life, this nonsense of patching up wins and losses
1分砕いて常識を 未来にセーグッバイ
Crushing common sense in a minute, say goodbye to the future
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度ナンセンス
My heart is an Ego Rock, a 45-degree angle of nonsense
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日にバイバイバイ
Crushing the know-how, breaking the rut, say bye-bye-bye to tomorrow
媚びへつらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That fawning appearance of yours is enough to make me sick
シニカルな視線の雨
A rain of cynical gazes
今日も両目を塞ぐふり ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー・ツー
Pretending to cover both eyes again today, one, two, three, four, two
はい！
Yes!
みんな！これ、見えとる？見えとる？
Everyone! Can you see this? Can you see?
あ、みんなのすげー驚いてる顔が団長見えとるよ！
Ah, I can see everyone's incredibly surprised faces!
あーい、団長でーす！おーい！
Alright, it's me! Hello!
ということで、ちょっと団長なんか変わったところ気づきましたか？
So, did you notice anything different about me?
まあ、気づいてない人はいないと思います。
Well, I don't think there's anyone who hasn't noticed.
団長なんと、なんと！
To my surprise, to my surprise!
今回ね、あの前々から運営さんにお願いしていた
This time, something I've been asking the management for a long time...
100万人記念の新衣装が出来上がりましたー！イエーイ！
My new outfit for the 1 million subscriber anniversary is ready! Yay!
今回はね、なんとそのお披露目も兼ねたライブになっていまして。
This live stream is also serving as its big reveal.
いや、びっくりしたっしょ？
Were you surprised?
いやね、めちゃめちゃ動きやすくなったんすよね。
It's become so much easier to move in.
いや、これ早くホロメンにも見てほしいなあ。
Man, I want the other Hololive members to see this soon.
誰かいいねえかなあ。
I wonder if anyone's around.
うぇーい！お姉ちゃん可愛い！団長ー！お姉ちゃんめっちゃ可愛い！
Whoo! You're cute, Sis! Master! You're so cute, Sis!
あれ？なんか聞こえる。
Huh? I hear something.
お姉ちゃん可愛い！
You're cute, Sis!
え、なんかこれ、おっさん？あれ？あ！
Wait, is that... some old guy? Huh? Ah!
唐突な前振りがあったな、今。
That was a pretty sudden setup just now.
怪しいおっさんかと思ったけど、あ、この声は。
I thought it was some shady old guy, but ah, this voice is...
えーと、じゃあ、ちょっとやかましいの「や」からよろしくお願いします。
Um, okay then, let's start with the 'A' for 'Annoying'.
求めてるよー！行け行けー！
I'm asking for it! Go go!
やかましいの「や」誰や！
Who's the annoying 'A'?!
あれ？ころねじゃないの？
Wait, isn't that Korone?
やかましいの「や」、あ、ころねです。
The annoying 'A', ah, it's Akone.
あ, ころねー！
Ah, Korone!
わーい！
Yay!
こっちは誰や？
And who's this one?
ラミィじゃない？
Isn't it Lamy?
ラミィです！
It's Lamy!
あ, ラミィ！
Ah, Lamy!
やかましいの「ま」、マリンです！
The annoying 'M', it's Marine!
あ、マリン！わかりやすいね、「ま」のマリン。
Ah, Marine! That's easy to understand, 'M' for Marine.
そうそう、
Right, right.
やかましの「し」、白銀ノエルー！
The "Shi" of Yakamashi, Shirogane Noel!
イエーイ！
Yay!
来てくれたんだね。
You came to see me.
ちょっとちょっと、下からさ、
Wait, wait. From below,
もっとアップで舐め回して。
give me a close-up, scan me all over.
そんな見たいんだ。
You want to see that much?
ちょっと研究してほしいな、下から。
I want you to research it a bit from below.
カメラマンさん、もっと、足元から、足元から。
Mr. Cameraman, more from the feet, from the feet.
足元からチェック。
Checking from the feet.
あ、この靴に騎士のマークが。
Ah, there's a knight's mark on these boots.
本当だ！
It's true!
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
はい、入ってますね。
Yes, it's there.
可愛い可愛い。
Cute, cute.
よいしょ、よいしょ。あー、なんか生足とか、恥ずかしいな。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Showing bare legs is embarrassing.
こっち側すごい。スリット入ってる。すごい。
This side is amazing. There's a slit. Wow.
うわっ！リボン付いてる。
Whoa! There are ribbons.
横も付いてます。
They're on the side too.
あら卑らしい、これ紐解いたらどうなっちゃうの？
How scandalous. What happens if these are untied?
紐解いたらもう大変だよ。しかもこれね、
It would be a disaster. And also, this...
外して、外して。
Take it off, take it off.
外せないよ、団長さんにそんなこと。
I can't take it off for the Commander.
紐解いて遊んじゃおうかな。
Maybe I'll untie the ribbons and play around.
キモ！
Gross!
後ろ、あー、様になってる。
The back, ah, it looks great.
可愛いー！
So cute!
あら、いいじゃん。
Oh, looking good.
えー、可愛いー。いいでしょ。
Ehh, so cute. Isn't it?
お洒落。なんか携帯ホルダーみたいについてるじゃん。
Stylish. It's got something like a phone holder.
何入ってんの？これ何？これ、あれだよ、メイスとかね。
What's in it? This is for the mace and stuff.
団長、踊ってたからメイスなかったんだけど、ちょっとメイス…
I didn't have my mace while dancing, but...
なるほどねー、なるほどねー。
I see, I see.
可愛いー。
So cute.
背中可愛くない？ちょっと。
Isn't the back cute? Just a bit.
えっ、背中！背中見える！背中！
Eh, the back! I can see the back! The back!
可愛いー！
So cute!
なぞっちゃうぞ。なぞっちゃうぞー。
I'm gonna trace it. I'm gonna trace it.
真ん中ちゅちゅちゅってなぞっちゃうぞー。
I'm gonna trace the middle with a touch.
おじさんいっぱいだ。あとメイス来たよ。
Middle-aged fans are here. Also, the mace is here.
あ、メイスだ！メイス！
Ah, the mace! Mace!
やっぱメイスないと落ち着かないからね、騎士として。
I can't feel at ease without my mace, being a knight.
重そう。おー。
Looks heavy. Ohh.
つけときます。
I'll keep it on.
胸元すごくない？それ。
Isn't the chest area amazing? That.
もっとアップで！おー、いいよいいよ、おじさんだ。
More close-ups! Nice, nice, you're a middle-aged fan.
あら、
Oh my,
振ってるのがさらにちょっと、あれだね。いい？
The way it's swinging is even more... Ready?
刺激的やね。
That's exciting.
収まらない、収まらないよ。
It won't stay put, it won't stay put.
脱げないのですか？
Can't you take it off?
脱げちゃうんだけど、ちょっとYouTube君がね、
I can take it off, but YouTube is a bit...
あー、ダメか。なるほどね。そうなんだ。
Ah, no good? I see. That's how it is.
カメラ。なんか手で隠して、手で隠してやりながら、
Camera. Hide it with your hands while doing it,
そうそうそう。これなら、ちょっと、ちょっと、
Yeah, yeah, yeah. With this, just a bit...
え、今外れた？外れた？
Wait, did it come off now? Did it?
まだ…あ、あー！
Not yet... Ah, ahh!
見せ見せ。あー！まだね、こんぐらい。チラ。チラリズムよ。
Show us. Ahh! Not yet, just this much. A peek.
すごい。いいじゃん。めちゃ可愛い。
Amazing. Looking good. So cute.
髪色も可愛い。髪の色。色の感じがね、違うよね。
The hair color is also cute. It's different, right?
そう、髪型ね、毛先がグラデ、
Right, the hairstyle, the tips are a gradient,
グラデおしゃになっちゃって。
a stylish gradient.
このピンも。都会に染まっちゃってー。
This clip too. You've been dyed by the city.
ねー。いいじゃん、グラデ具合よ。
Right. Looking good, that gradient level.
今流行りのって感じ。あらよ、
Feels like what's trending now. Oh my,
いい、そのヘアピン欲しいわ。
Nice, I want that hair clip.
本当。グッズで欲しいです、欲しいです。
Really. I want it as merchandise, I want it.
あ、そんな言葉、ちょっと覚えといて。グッズで欲しい、わかった。
Ah, remember those words. I'll make it as merch.
言質取ったからね。言質取ったから！
I've got your word on it. I've got your word!
後ろポニテ見せてよ。
Show us the ponytail from the back.
ポニテ、いいよ。あ、ポニテ！可愛いー！
Ponytail, sure. Ah, ponytail! So cute!
独特なんだよな。団長、動きがね。振り返って、
Her movement is so unique. Turn around,
振り返ってー、あっ、やっちゃったよ、ワッキー！
Turn around... Ah, she did it, Wacky!
いいじゃん、可愛い。ワッキー！
Looking good, cute. Wacky!
そう最近ね、といえばなんだっけ。あれなの。そう、みんなさ、天の声だと思って油断しとるでしょ。
You're all letting your guard down thinking it's
just a voice from above, aren't you?
はいはい。違うの、みんなおるよ。ちょっと待っとってね。
No, everyone's here. Wait a moment.
おるの？おるのちゃん？
They are? Are they there?
はい、おらへんよ。あ、おる。おるわ。みんな来い来い。待って待って。
Yes, they're... wait, they are! Come here, everyone.
おらへんだろ、逆にそんなの。おらへんだろ、何だよ。
They wouldn't be there. They wouldn't be there!
大変だよ。みんな持ってきたよ、マリンです。
It's a big deal. I brought everyone. I'm Marine.
似てねー。全然似てないよ。
Not even close. Not similar at all.
見てほら、やかましい。嬉しいな。
Look, see, it's Yakamashi. I'm so happy.
何でマリンに被ってきたお前。
Why did you overlap with Marine?
被ってくんな。このポーズちょっと、やりたい、真似するの？
Don't overlap. I want to do this pose.
あ、やってるやってる。じゃあやかましの「や」から順番に。
They're doing it. Starting from 'Ya' of Yakamashi.
「や」から行こうか。「や」から行こうか。よし、
Let's start from 'Ya'. Let's start from 'Ya'.
よろしくね。やかましの「こ」、あ、こうか。
The 'Ko' of Yakamashi... Ah, like this?
足をね、広げて広げて。広げて。いいよ、いいじゃん、可愛いー！
Spread your legs, spread them. Spread them. So cute!
このポーズ。なんかファンのオタクみたいになってる、なんか。
This pose. It's like I've become a fanboy.
私と同じポーズ取ってみた、みたいな。で、えーと、やか「ま」だね。「ま」。
Like, 'I tried taking the same pose as me.' And, uh, it's the 'Ma' of Yakama. 'Ma'.
あ、マリンの。いいよ、いいよ。アイドル感。あ、可愛い。
Ah, Marine's. Nice. Idol vibes. Ah, cute.
エプロン大変だね。あ、いいよ、頑張ってます。
The apron is tough. Ah, you're doing your best.
いいよいいよ、いい感じ、いい感じ。できてるよ。
Looking good, looking good. You've got it.
ちょっとクソ絶妙なポーズ取れるかな、これ。角度が大事。
Can I pull off this subtle pose? Angle is key.
（笑い声）
(Laughter)
何このポーズ！
What is this pose?!
もうジョジョやん、こんなん！
This is totally like JoJo!
あ、リンボーダンスかな？
Oh, is it a limbo dance?
リンボーダンス…
Limbo dance...
いや、ちょっと何も取れないよ、この距離じゃ！
Wait, I can't catch anything from this distance!
ころねんの、て、手、リンボーダンス…
Korone's hand-limbo dance...
（笑い声）
(Laughter)
すごいね、何でもできるんだね、すごい！
Amazing, you can do anything! Wow!
何でもできる装備になったんだ、今日ね！
I've got the equipment to do anything today!
やっぱね、動きやすい衣装をお願いしてて…
Yeah, I asked for an outfit that's easy to move in...
せっかく動きやすい衣装になったから、何かポーズ取ってもらうか、何かね？
Since you've got this easy-to-move outfit, why not strike some poses?
確かにね、やかまし恒例のスリーロットポーズもやりますか！
True, shall we do the usual Yakamashi 'three-slot' pose?
やりましょう！やりましょう！
Let's do it! Let's do it!
じゃあちょっと待ってね、みんなが見えてほしいから…
Wait a sec, I want everyone to be visible, so...
やかま…えーと、ま、こんな感じで！
Yakamashi... well, something like this!
じゃあ、頭スロットはじゃあ、ラミィ行こうかな？
Okay, for the head slot, shall we go with Lamy?
頭ラミィ！うん、頭ラミィで行こうか！
Lamy for the head! Yeah, let's go with head-Lamy!
で、上半身は？
And the upper body?
上半身じゃあ、マ、マリン！船長が担当します！
For the upper body, Ma-Marine! The Captain will take charge!
じゃあころね下半身で！シリュリュリュリュ…
Then Korone for the lower body! *drumroll sounds*
えー、まず顔はやっぱり髪型を見せたいから、こう！
First, for the face, I want to show off the hair, so like this!
ちょっと横向いてもらって、あ、そっちだね。で、ウィンクとかにしようかな？
Turn to the side a bit... ah, that way. And how about a wink?
あ、なるほどウィンク！あ、そう。で、ちょっと首かしげてほしいな！
Ah, I see, a wink! Right. And I'd like a slight head tilt!
あー、いいいいいい！いいよ、なるほどね、オッケー！
Ah, nice, nice, nice! That's good. I see, okay!
じゃあ、上半身はね、ちょっと屈み気味にして…
Now, for the upper body, lean forward a bit...
お、お、お、どうだ？お胸が重そうで大変だから、手で持ち上げて！
Oh, oh, oh, how's that? It looks heavy on the chest, so hold them up with your hands!
（笑い声）いいよいいよいいよ！はい、なるほどね！
(Laughter) Nice, nice, nice! Okay, I see!
下半身はね、じゃあ、できる限り開いてもらって…
As for the lower body, well, spread them as wide as you can...
怪しくなってきたぞ！結構開く！結構開く！
This is getting suspicious! That's quite wide! Quite wide!
で、ちょっと内股みたいな。難しいな、何だこのポーズ、プルプルするぞ！
And then, sort of pigeon-toed. This is tough! What is this pose? I'm shaking!
あ、膝ついてもらおうかな、そしたら！膝つきね、そのまま…
Ah, how about kneeling then! On your knees, just like that...
あ、いいじゃん！あー！首！首！もっと屈んで！もっと！
Oh, that's great! Ah! Your head! Your head! Lean down more! More!
とんでもないよ、このポーズ！いいじゃん！ウィンク！ウィンク！
This pose is outrageous! It's good! Wink! Wink!
一人だけおかしいって、ポーズ！全然ウィンクじゃない！
One of these poses is just wrong! That's not a wink at all!
これでも正解スロットだよ、これ！いいと思うよ！やかましで見てみるか！
But this is the 'correct' slot! I think it's great! Let's check it with Yakamashi!
一人だけ座ってるじゃん！ありがとう！このポーズ大事にしていくわ！
One of them is just sitting! Thank you! I'll cherish this pose!
じゃあこの後もいっぱい歌って踊るから、三人は特等席で見ててくだせえよ！
Well, I'll be singing and dancing plenty more, so you three, watch from the best seats!
最前で見てますよ！お目に焼き付けるわ！頑張って！
We'll watch from the front row! We'll burn it into our eyes! Good luck!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！応援してるよ！頑張れ！
Thank you! Bye-bye! We're rooting for you! Go for it!
シリウス
Sirius
誰かが勝手に決めた 既製品(レディーメイド)な
A ready-made one decided by someone else
今日を賑わせて 裸足で走ってゆく
Enlivening today, I'll run barefoot
間違ったって 転んだって
Even if I make mistakes, even if I fall
振り向いた痛みも オリジナルな明日になる
The pain I look back on will become an original tomorrow
突き上げたこの手に 握り締めた
In this hand I thrust upward, I grasped tight
誓いが 光になって
The oath became a light
誓いが光になって
My vow turns into light
いつか君に届く
And will someday reach you
その瞬間まで
Until that very moment
泣いてる暇なんてないから
I have no time to be crying
はみ出してしまった熱い想いが夜空で
My overflowing passion
輝き出す
Starts to shine in the night sky
生まれてきた意味が分かった気がした
I feel like I've understood the meaning of my life
願い事は全部この手で叶える
I'll grant all my wishes with these hands
不安に抗うだけで精一杯で
Just fighting off my anxiety took all I had
震えてしまっていた昨日があったけど
There were days when I was trembling yesterday
立ち止まってたそんな時間も
Even those times when I was standing still
必要だったのかななんて今はね思える
Now I can feel like they were necessary
暗闇を切り裂き辿り着いた
Cutting through the darkness, I reached it
景色のその向こうに
Beyond the scenery
いつも君がちゃんと待っててくれてた
You were always waiting for me right there
愛おしく煌めく世界で
In this precious and sparkling world
流星群追い越し
Passing the meteor shower
高く高く心が叫ぶ先へ
High and higher, to where my heart screams
もらっている以上にあげられるように
So I can give back even more than I receive
ねえ未来は全部この手で叶える
Hey, I'll grant the entire future with these hands
痛く抱えていた夜も
Nights I held onto the pain
涙で迎えた朝もどんな時も
Mornings I met with tears, through it all
眩い青星みたいに
Like a dazzling blue star
突き上げたこの手に握り締めた
Holding tight in my raised hands
誓いが光になって
My vow turns into light
いつか君に届くその瞬間まで
Until that very moment it reaches you
泣いてる暇なんてないから
I have no time to be crying
はみ出してしまった熱い想いが夜空で
My overflowing passion
輝き出す
Starts to shine in the night sky
生まれてきた意味が分かった気がした
I feel like I've understood the meaning of my life
願い事は全部この手で叶える
I'll grant all my wishes with these hands
そう未来は全部この手で叶える
Yes, I'll grant the entire future with these hands
はい！はい、どうでしたか？
Alright! Well, how was that?
団長の「シリウス」でした！
That was your Knight Leader's 'Sirius'!
いや、これはね、ちょっと匂わせてたの、気づいたかな？
I was hinting at this a little, did you notice?
団長、最近の歌枠とかで、ちょっと練習してたので
I've been practicing it in recent singing streams
いや、もしかしたらライブこれ歌うんじゃないかなって
I think some people might have thought,
思ってた人もいると思うんですけど、その人は正解です！
'Maybe she'll sing this at the live' - and you were right!
っていう感じで、いや本当に、あの、ライブもだんだんと終盤に...
And so, really, the live is gradually nearing the end...
終盤どころか、もうあと一曲...いや、まだまだ！
Actually, past the end, there's only one song left... Wait, not yet!
ちょっとね、ここで、「え、もう一曲なら、ちょっといいか」と思って
Right now, if you're thinking, 'Eh, only one song left, I'm good,'
ブラウザバックしようとしたそこの君！なんと重大告知が、
and trying to click back! Well, I have a major announcement...
ドゥルルルルルル...ジャン！二つ、あります！
Drumroll please... Ta-da! I have two of them!
いや、一つはね、たぶん想像つくと思うんですけど...
I think you can probably guess one of them, but...
まあ、まずは、ちょっと一つ目から発表したいと思います！
Well, first, I'd like to announce the first one!
なんだろうな？ドゥー...ドン！
What could it be? Drumroll... Bang!
白銀ノエル、3D新衣装記念2022グッズが発売されます！
Shirogane Noel's 3D New Costume Celebration 2022 merchandise is now on sale!
ドンドンパフパフパフパフ！
*Celebratory noises*
ということでね、まあ詳細の方、ちょっと話していくとですね
So, to go into the details a bit...
あの、今回、まあ、こうやって新衣装になりました。
This time, well, I've got this new costume.
そう、100万人記念の衣装が、こうやって運営さんに、はい、いただいて...
Yes, I received this 100-million subscriber celebration outfit from management...
やっぱ衣装でね
After all, with the outfit,
アクリルスタンド欲しいんじゃないかなと思ったので
I thought you might want an acrylic stand,
団長この新衣装記念してアクリルスタンド、はい、作ってみました
so I've made an acrylic stand to celebrate this new outfit.
ま、団長が、ま、これあれですよ、撮ったんですよ
I actually... I took the photo for this!
そう、団長が撮りました
Yes, I took it myself.
っていう感じで、ぜひぜひあの、通常でね
And so, please, we have the regular one,
あの、常設で、白銀ノエル、普通の、アクリルスタンドも
the permanent Shirogane Noel regular acrylic stand
絶賛販売中なので
is also currently on sale,
もしよければ、二つ、あの、並べて飾ってください
so if you'd like, please display the two together.
他はね、あの、星願先生描き下ろしの、ランダムキーホルダー
Next is the random keyholder illustrated by Hoshinegai-sensei.
団長ね、こんこよちゃんとかがランダムキーホルダーしてるの見て
I saw Koyori-chan and others with random keyholders
いいなーと思って
and thought they were great.
なので団長もね、すごいリリカルな動きをしたこのキーホルダーも
So I also made this keyholder with very lyrical movements,
ぜひぜひゲットしてみてください
please try to get it.
で、あとは、これが一番ちょっと目玉かも
And next, this might be the main highlight,
しれないんですけど
actually.
あの、団長のこの、ここら辺の紋章をあしらった
A tie pin featuring my emblem from right around here
ネクタイピンを用意いたしました
has been prepared.
なので、白銀聖騎士団のネクタイピン
So, the Shirogane Holy Knight Order Tie Pin,
こちらもぜひぜひ着けて
please wear this too
はい、今後ちょっとね、お外とかお出かけしていただければと思います
and take it with you when you go out.
カバンにはね、星願ちゃんのあのランダムキーホルダー
On your bag, you can put Hoshinegai-chan's random keyholder,
団長のぺって着けて、まずはフルセットでね
slap on the Captain, and if you buy the full set,
買っていただくと、なんと
believe it or not,
あの、団長のチェキ風ブロマイドカードも
you also get my cheki-style bromide card
ついてくるので、複製サイン入りなので、ぜひぜひそちらもゲットしてください
with a printed signature, so please get that too.
ランダムキーホルダーはね、他にちょっとフルセットで買って
As for the random keyholders, you could buy the full set
さらに単品で、みたいなのがいいんじゃないかなと思います
and then some individual ones as well.
という感じで、ま、これが重大告知1なんですけど
So, that was major announcement #1,
重大告知2は
but major announcement #2...
これから、ちょっとあの、お披露目していきたいと思います
I'm going to reveal it to you now.
今日のライブ、なんとリリカルライブだったと思うんですけど
Today's live was the "Lyrical LIVE",
その、ま、元になったものです
and this is the thing that inspired it.
ではでは、お披露目したいと思いますので
Now then, I'm going to reveal it,
ぜひぜひ最後まで聴いててねー
so please listen until the very end!
えい！
Ei!
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong
鼓動がBeat it 期待もHeat up 感じて
My heartbeat is Beating, the anticipation is Heating up, feel it
リリカルMonster
Lyrical Monster
Joy! Joy! もっとエンジョイ
Joy! Joy! Enjoy more
リリカルStreaming
Lyrical Streaming
上々気分
Feeling great
つよつよHomeRun
Strong, strong Home Run
団長真の才能
Captain's true talent
リリカルKeyword
Lyrical Keyword
見せてあげる
I'll show you
Lovely Party
ぴゅるるーんる ぴゅるるーんる
Pyururunru Pyururunru
巻き起こる言霊Typhoon
An arising Kotodama Typhoon
もっとHappy
More Happy
トコトントコトン弾けちゃうよ
Tokoton-tokoton, let's pop
そうだろう 困ろう
That's right, let's be troubled
トキメキたろう
Let's feel the heartbeat
La La Lovit いかがですか？
La La Lovit, how is it?
ちょっとVivid感じたら
If you feel it's a bit Vivid
止めらんない
Can't stop it
とめどないくらい胸のドキドキ同期
A synchronous heartbeat that won't stop
一周回って現在進行
Coming full circle, it's currently in progress
ぐるぐる追いかけっこ
Round and round, playing tag
アラララ la mode
A-la-la-la la mode
このままいくよ
Keep going like this
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong
鼓動がBeat it
My heartbeat is Beating
期待もHeat up
Anticipation is Heating up
もっと感じて
Feel it more
Jumping Jumping
ディスプレイをJamming
Jamming the display
おさんぽ気分新世代ライ
Take a walk feeling like a new generation lie
異論反論は認めません
No objections or counterarguments allowed
史上最高のコトバマイスター
The best Word Meister in history
U&I ここからReady
U&I Ready from here
ずっと見てて リリカルMonster キラ
Keep watching, Lyrical Monster, sparkling
まっする かます
Muscle, show 'em
意気揚々Boom Boom
Triumphant, Boom Boom
もっとお騒げ
Make more noise
Put your hands up Boom Boom
Talkだけじゃない
It's not just Talk
Not 脳筋
Not muscle-brained
ほめてのびて 有頂天であびゃあびゃ
Growing through praise, in ecstasy, abya-abya
テンパる脳内Typhoon
Panicked inside the brain, Typhoon
やっぱCrazy
After all, it's Crazy
ビシバシビシバシ 震えちゃうよ
Bishibashi-bishibashi, I'm shaking
Give me a love
キミはLaugh
You Laugh
ゆうずうむげ おかわりいかがですか？
Unfettered, how about a second helping?
もっとVivid感じてよ
Feel more Vivid
やめらんない
Can't stop
目が離せない キミのハッシュタグHack
Can't take my eyes off, your hashtag Hack
もっかい回って通常運転
One more rotation, normal operation
のびのび いつも通り
Carefree, as always
アラララ a la carte
A-la-la-la a la carte
そのままいくよ
Keep going like that
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong
予測は不能
Unpredictable
想像以上のShow timeするから
It'll be a Show time beyond your imagination
Bumping Bumping
騎士団もPanic
The order is also in Panic
突拍子ない発言も寛容
Tolerate any unpredictable remarks
凡庸なんじゃありません
I'm not mediocre
空前絶後のコトバマジシャン
The unprecedented Word Magician
Yes or Yes なんでもAlright
Yes or Yes, anything is Alright
一緒にSinging リリカルなスター Amazing
Singing together, a lyrical star, Amazing
みんな団長のリリカルLIVE今日は来てくれて
Everyone, thank you for coming to my Lyrical LIVE today!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんでリリカルモンスターって言ってたかわかったでしょ？
Now you know why I called it Lyrical Monster, right?
最後まで盛り上がっていってね！
Keep the excitement going until the very end!
いつもとは違う風もあるよ
There are winds different from usual
そこがイイところ
That's the good part
どんな日も笑顔にするからさ
Because I'll make every day a smile
どんどん笑って相乗効果
Keep laughing for a synergistic effect
ニコニコ100点満点
Smiling 100 points
アラララLove & Peace
Ala-la-la Love & Peace
このままいくよ
Keeping it going like this
まだまだいくよ
Keep it going more and more
ついてきてよね
Follow me, okay?
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong みんななら
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong, if it's all of you
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong 出来るはずさ
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong, you should be able to do it
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong 聞かせて
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong, let me hear you
Ring-Dong-Dong 大きな声で
Ring-Dong-Dong, with a loud voice
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong 鼓動がBeat it
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong, heartbeat is Beat it
期待もHeat up もっと感じて
Expectations also Heat up, feel it more
Jumping Jumping ディスプレイをJamming
Jumping Jumping, Jamming the display
ゆるふわ太郎　ハピネス太郎
Yurufuwa-taro, Happiness-taro
異議反論は認めません
Objections and counter-arguments are not accepted
史上最高の団長だから
Because I'm the best Knight Captain in history
ますますLoving
More and more Loving
一緒にSinging
Singing together
It's Amazing!
リリカルモンスター降臨
Lyrical Monster Descent
はーい！新衣装と新曲お披露目ライブ、どうでしたでしょうか？
Hi! How was the new outfit and new song reveal live?
楽しんでもらえたなら団長嬉しいです！
Captain is happy if you enjoyed it!
そしてね、ここでちょっとだけお知らせがあります。
And now, I have a little announcement here.
なんと！なんと！このライブ中にホロライブ公式スタンプ「白銀ノエル」が発売されました！
なんと！なんと！ During this live, the Hololive official stamp "Shirogane Noel" has been released!
もう現在ね、もうLINE多分買えると思うので、こちらもぜひぜひ買ってください。
You can probably buy it on LINE now, so please do check it out.
いーっぱいLINEしてください。
Send lots of LINEs.
まあLINEする友達がいない人は、団長とイマジナリーに友達になりましょう。
Well, for those who don't have friends to LINE, let's become imaginary friends with the Captain.
そして、後日このライブの感想会をするんですが、その時に...
And, I'll be having a post-live review session later, and at that time...
団員さんの、まあビジュアルを発表しようと思います！お待たせして申し訳ございません！
I'm planning to announce the visual for the fans! Sorry for the wait!
3Dライブ感想会で！団員さんビジュアルお披露目します！わくわく待っててねっ！
I'll reveal the fan visuals at the 3D live review session! Wait for it excitedly!
や、ぜひぜひ感想会も、うん、来てもらえると嬉しいです！
Yes, I'd be happy if you could join the review session too!
ではでは、他のね、いっぱいたくさんホロメンが素敵な配信をしてると思うので、
Well then, I'm sure many other Holomen are doing wonderful streams,
団長はお暇します。
so the Captain will take her leave.
皆さん、これからもよろしくね！大好きだぞ！ん～まっ！
Everyone, please look forward to working with me! I love you all! Muah!
団員さんのおかげで新しい姿がもらえたよ♪ 不器用なノエちゃんだけどこれからもアイドルを目指してがんばります！！ Noel
Thanks to the fans, I got a new look♪ I'm a clumsy Noel-chan, but I'll keep doing my best to be an idol!! Noel